# **Jeff Wymore**

## Web/Software Developer

JeffWymore78@gmail.com https://github.com/yardboy2401 https://yardboy2401.github.io/portfolio-reactjs-wymore/ www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-wymore-jw78

425-772-9869 • Wenatchee, WA

### Qualifications Summary

Coding bootcamp graduate with extensive experience in several coding languages, developing mobile-first applications, and building websites from the ground up. Specializing in JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML/CSS, MySQL, and MongoDB.

Professional strengths include root cause analysis, problem solving, excellent written and verbal communication, and exceptional time management skills. Detail-oriented mindset from 15+ years of experience in the tech industry. Skilled technician and engineer with extensive experience in the field. Broad vocational background with various types of equipment. Able to learn concepts quickly and accurately.

#### **Technical Skills**

### Languages/Tools

- JavaScript/jQuery
- Bootstrap/Materialize CSS Frameworks
- HTML/CSS
- Agile Methodology
- Git

### **Applications**

- MySQL/Sequelize
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- Node/Express.js
- React.js/Vue
- GraphQL/Apollo

### **Projects**

### **Tailor Thrift (Group Project)**

**GitHub Link:** <a href="https://github.com/yardboy2401/tailorthrift-wymore">https://github.com/yardboy2401/tailorthrift-wymore</a> **Heroku Live Link:** <a href="https://tailorthrift-wymore.herokuapp.com/">https://tailorthrift-wymore</a>.

Full stack application for an online thrift store specializing in purchasing dress clothing with professional tailoring options for lower income individuals.

I setup the user JWT-Authentication and login/logout/signup screens, payment processing, Nodemailer-React and worked on the Global State Reducers/Context for the React.js front end. The following tools and languages were used.

- React.js front end
- MongoDB/GraphQL back end
- PWA w/ IndexedDB

- Node.js/Express.js
- Nodemailer-React
- Authentication w/ JWT tokens

### **Piece of Cake Bakery (Group Project)**

**GitHub Link:** <a href="https://github.com/yardboy2401/project2-pieceofcake">https://github.com/yardboy2401/project2-pieceofcake</a> **Heroku Live Link:** <a href="https://project2-pieceofcake.herokuapp.com/">https://project2-pieceofcake.herokuapp.com/</a>

Full stack application for a bakery with online ordering utilizing MySQL database, Node.js/Express.js and Express-Handlebars view engine for the front end. Followed MVC paradigm for file structure, NPM-Stripe payment processing and Express-Session Authentication.

I set up the user authentication, store page shopping cart, NPM-Stripe payment processing and NPM-Nodemailer automated email with new user creation. The following tools & languages were used:

- Node.js/Express.js
- Express-Handlebars

- NPM-Stripe/Nodemailer
- Express-Session Authentication

### **Movies and Cocktails (Group Project)**

GitHub Link: <a href="https://github.com/JonkHunkle/Project-1">https://github.com/JonkHunkle/Project-1</a>
GitHub Live Link: <a href="https://jonkhunkle.github.io/Project-1/">https://jonkhunkle.github.io/Project-1/</a>

Front end application for a movie and cocktail search. Using API calls to OMDB Movie and Cocktail databases to display movie search results and randomly suggest cocktails based on movie genre.

I created the cocktail drink carousel and cocktail image on second page with drink recipe. Assisted with some of the Materialize styling and grid setup for the layout of main page and recipe page.

### Career Experience

### **Software Engineering Immersive**

September 2021 - March 2022

Developed several mobile applications and built two user-friendly websites using full stack JavaScript/NodeJS/ReactJS and several other programming languages, libraries, and frameworks

#### **Noted Projects:**

- Created an interactive weather dashboard using 2 separate API calls to display current weather and a 5-day extended forecast for any city searched. The search history stored to browser local storage for easy access. Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery.
- Created a timed and interactive code quiz game using the browser local storage for saving the high score. Game included a timer deduction as a penalty for missed question(s). Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

### **Electronic Service Technician (Van Doren Sales)**

February 2019 - July 2021

Install and support fruit-sorting equipment at client locations. Setup and configure the computer network. Calibrate the camera and lighting requirements for the equipment to function properly. Designated as the on-call technician to repair and troubleshoot equipment. Perform service calls in the Wenatchee area and utilize company truck and equipment to perform assignments.

### Site Engineer-Seattle (Ion Beam Applications – IBA)

March 2018 to November 2018

Conducted daily proton therapy center protocols, which included start-up procedures, software updates, and testing. Tasked to operate the proton therapy system. Performed duties during high-stress situations caused by system downtime events occurring during clinical patient treatments. Initiated and promoted continuous client communication concerning the status of the system. Engaged in scheduled maintenance to the patient positioning system, treatment room nozzle components, and the x-ray equipment.

#### Field Service Engineer (Ion Beam Applications - IBA)

August 2016 – March 2018

Tasked to perform preventative maintenance and repair of proton therapy equipment/systems. Updated cooling and vacuum systems drivers, fiber-optic cables, high and low voltage supply equipment, patient-positioning equipment, PLCs, regulation loops, sensors, and x-ray system. Repaired and calibrated robotics systems. Traveled throughout the United States to maintain, repair, and upgrade equipment.

### **Customer Service Supervisor (Sea-Bird Electronics, Inc.)**

June 2011 to August 2016

Oversaw the Customer Service group comprised of twelve technicians assigned to support highly specialized oceanographic equipment. Supplied technical leadership to the technicians who were tasked to maintain and service the entire Sea-Bird product line. Prepared and participated in 6S/Kaizen/QDIP activities. Utilized LEAN manufacturing management principles.

### **Education**

- <u>Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington, Seattle, WA</u>
   24-week intensive software development bootcamp focusing on front-end and back-end technologies, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap/Materialize/Tailwind CSS frameworks, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Git, VSCode, GitHub, and much more. Simulated professional work environment by teaming up with classmates on real-word projects. Followed model agile environment, based on creating and responding to user stories.</u>
- Naval Nuclear Power School

24-week nuclear and atomic theory, algebra, calculus, chemistry, materials, physics, radiological controls, and thermodynamics.

### Naval Nuclear Field 'A' School

17-week electrical/electronic, mechanical theory, and motor/generator class, including diagrams, electrical schematics, and mechanical drawings. Topics included calibration, diagnostic test equipment maintenance, and troubleshooting techniques.

#### Naval Nuclear Prototype School

26-week hands-on training, including maintenance and operations on the 450V AC/DC electric plant, operation of the engine room and reactor on the S5W Reactor Plant, and radiological controls.